<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Nerd Chess</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <!-- select player activity -->
    <string name="white_player">FIRST PLAYER</string>
    <string name="black_player">SECOND PLAYER</string>
    <string name="confirm_white_player_button">Confirm</string>
    <string name="confirm_black_player_button">Confirm</string>

    <!-- settings -->
    <string name="vibration">Toggle Vibration</string>
    <string name="sound">Toggle Sound</string>
    <string name="music">Toggle Music</string>
    <string name="background">Background Picture</string>
    <string name="theme">Theme</string>
    <string name="background_music">Background Music</string>

    <!-- exit dialog in play activity -->
    <string name="exit_dialog">Are you sure you want to quit this game?</string>
    <string name="positive_button">Yes</string>
    <string name="negative_button">No</string>

    <!-- tutorial -->
    <string name="tutorial_title">Instant Tutorial</string>
    <string name="tutorial_first_part">
        Welcome in NerdChess, a game app in which you can play a fantasy-themed chess-like game.
		\nThis tiny tutorial will give you enough instructions to start playing a game asap. If you want to read the game rules,
          go on with the next sections.
		\nThere are three choices of game you can make in this app:
			\n\t1. 2P Local game: you can play a match against a human opponent on the same device
			\n\t2. 1P Ai game: you can play a match against an artificial intelligence, which has two levels of difficulty: easy and hard
			\n\t3. 2P Online game: you can play a match against another human opponent even remotely; in this mode, both players will need
                   access to a network connection
		\nOnce you’ve selected one of the three choices, you can start a game.
    </string>
    <string name="tutorial_second_part">
        In the picture above you can see how a game is structured.
		\nAt the top of the screen there is a text which you should read to know the next actions to accomplish: which turn it is,
          what action should this player perform.
		\nBelow that, there is a chessboard on which there are the pieces: first (white) player’s pieces on the left and his opponent’s
          (black) pieces on the right. Above each piece you can see a numbered bar, indicating its vitality; as soon as it reaches zero,
          the piece dies and is removed from the game. A player, in his turn, can touch only one among the pieces of his color.
          After a piece has been selected, some of the buttons below the chessboard will be highlited, based on which actions
          are available for that piece.
    </string>
    <string name="tutorial_third_part">
        As you can see from the picture above, there are six buttons, one for moving a piece, one for attacking and the other four
        to cast spells (only available to the mage). Starting from left to right:
			\n\t- M, allows a piece to move to any legal cell on the board within its move range
			\n\t- A, allows a piece to attack any enemy piece within its attack range
			\n\t- F, allows the mage to freeze an opponent piece
			\n\t- H, allows the mage to heal an allied piece
			\n\t- R, allows the mage to revive an allied piece
			\n\t- T, allows the mage to teleport an allied piece from its cell to a target cell
		\nFinally, at the bottom of the screen there are two buttons:
			\n\t- Back button: when it’s pressed, you go back to the menu saving the state of the game; be aware that if you start a different type of game or enter different player names, the game will be resumed from zero
			\n\t- Restart button: click this button if you want to resume a new game from the start

		\n\nIf you want to continue reading the game rules, press next button on top of the screen.
    </string>

    <!-- game rules in classic_help activity -->
    <string name="first_help_page">1/9</string>
    <string name="second_help_page">2/9</string>
    <string name="third_help_page">3/9</string>
    <string name="fourth_help_page">4/9</string>
    <string name="fifth_help_page">5/9</string>
    <string name="sixth_help_page">6/9</string>
    <string name="seventh_help_page">7/9</string>
    <string name="eighth_help_page">8/9</string>
    <string name="ninth_help_page">9/9</string>

    <string name="game_description_title">Game Description</string>
    <string name="game_rules_title">Game Rules</string>
    <string name="piece_types_title">Piece Types</string>
    <string name="game_move_rules_title">Move Rules</string>
    <string name="game_attack_rules_title">Attack Rules</string>
    <string name="game_combat_rules_title">Combat Rules</string>
    <string name="mages_and_squires_rules_title">Mages and Squires</string>
    <string name="spells_rules_title">Spells Rules</string>
    <string name="end_of_game_rules_title">End of Game Rules</string>

    <string name="game_description">
        NerdChess is a chess-like board game, but its rules are even easier:
        \n• There are two players, each with a color (default colors are white and black) and a number of pieces of different kinds
        \n• The board consists of 6x6 cells
        \n• The goal is to occupy three out of four special cells (highlighted in orange) in the board with one’s own pieces or to kill
        all the opponent’s pieces
    </string>
    <string name="game_rules">
        The game rules are the following:
        \n• White moves first
        \n• Players alternate turns in a round robin fashion
        \n• A turn consists in one of the following actions:
            \n\t– Moving a chosen piece of one’s own side
            \n\t– Attacking an opponent’s piece
            \n\t– Casting a spell
        \n• Each piece type has different characteristics:
            \n\t– The way it can move on the board
            \n\t– The way it can attack other pieces
            \n\t– Its vitality
        \n• The effect of an attack is to reduce an opponent’s piece vitality
        \n• If vitality is 0, the piece is killed and removed from the board
        \n• The goal is to occupy three special cells or to kill all of the opponent’s pieces
    </string>
    <string name="piece_types">
        The pieces have the following stats:
        <!--\n\tInitial Vitality        \tMove                    \tAttack
                                \n\t\tRange Directions Type   \tRange Strength Directions
        \nGiant   5                       \t2   horiz+vert walk        \t1    4       horiz/vert
        \nDragon  6                       \t3   horiz+vert flight      \t2    3       horiz/vert
        \nMage    7                       \t1   any walk               \tn.a. 2       n.a.
        \nArcher  5                       \t2   any walk               \t3    2       horiz/vert
        \nSquire  3                       \t1   horiz+vert walk        \tn.a. 1       n.a.
        \nKnight  4                       \t1   any walk               \t1    2       diagonal-->
    </string>
    <string name="game_move_rules">
        The rules regarding the move of the pieces are the following:
        \n• A piece can either “walk” or “fly” in the specified directions (horizontally, vertically or diagonally) of
        up to as many cells as allowed by the move range
        \n• Flying means that the piece can land to any cell in its range regardless of whether the cells it crosses
        are occupied or not (i.e., “flying over” the cells)
        \n• Walking means that the piece can only move through empty cells
        \n• In both cases, the destination cell can be either empty or occupied by an opponent’s piece
    </string>
    <string name="game_attack_rules">
        The rules regarding the attack of the pieces are the following:
        \n• A piece A can attack an opponent’s piece B if
            \n\t– B is within A’s attack range along one of the allowed attack directions
            \n\t\t• Unlike moves, the same direction must be kept for the entire range (e.g., an Archer can attack 3 cells horizontally,
            but not 2 horizontally + 1 vertically)
            \n\t– There is no other piece between A and B along the attack direction
        \n• When B is attacked by A
            \n\t– B’s vitality is diminished by an amount equal to A’s strength; vitality can go down to a minimum of 0
            \n\t– If B’s vitality goes to 0, B is killed and removed from the board
    </string>
    <string name="game_combat_rules">
        The rules regarding the combat among pieces are the following:
        \n• If a move makes a piece arrive at a cell occupied by an opponent’s piece, they start a combat
            \n\t– At the end of the combat, one of the pieces (or both) will be killed, depending on their vitality and attack strength
        \n• The combat happens in the moving player’s turn and works as follows:
            \n\t– Both pieces diminish their vitality by an amount equal to their opponent’s strength
            \n\t– This is repeated until one or both pieces are killed
        \n• Special cases (interaction with spells):
            \n\t– If one of the two pieces is frozen (see spells, later), the frozen piece is killed
            and the other piece preserves its vitality unchanged
            \n\t– If both pieces are frozen (might happen by teleport, see spells), both are killed
        \n• Example: If a Giant with vitality 5 (strength 4) combats against a Mage with vitality 7 (strength 2), at the end
        of the combat the Mage is killed and the Giant remains alive with vitality 1
    </string>
    <string name="mages_and_squires_rules">
        For what regards mages and squires, they follow some different rules with respect to the other pieces:
        \n• Mages and Squires cannot perform attacks
            \n\t– Their attack range is 0
            \n\t– They can engage in combats, though, so their strength is greater than 0
        \n• Mages can cast spells
            \n\t– Any spell can only be cast once by a mage
            \n\t– No spell can involve a special cell or a cell where a mage lies
            \n\t– If the player’s mage is killed or frozen, the player cannot cast any spell
    </string>
    <string name="spells_rules">
        The rules regarding the spells cast by the mage are the following:
        \n• Heal: restore the initial vitality of a player’s piece
            \n\t– The piece cannot be in a special cell! The piece cannot be the mage!
            \n\t– The piece cannot be killed
        \n• Teleport: move a selected piece to any cell
            \n\t– The source cell must be occupied by a player’s piece
            \n\t– The destination cell must be either free or occupied by an opponent’s piece (in the latter case there will be a combat)
            \n\t– Neither cell can be special. Neither cell can be occupied by a mage.
        \n\t• Freeze: a selected opponent’s piece is frozen (and thus cannot move and cannot
        attack) for the opponent’s next 3 turns. Right at the end of the opponent’s 3rd turn, it’s unfrozen
            \n\t– The piece must not be in a special cell. The piece must not be a mage.
        \n• Revive: bring back a player’s killed piece with its initial vitality and unfrozen
            \n\t– Its new position will be the initial position
                \n\t\t• A squire or knight may also be brought back to the position of its twin
            \n\t– The revived piece’s new position must be either free or occupied by an opponent’s piece
                \n\t\t• in the latter case there will be a combat
    </string>
    <string name="end_of_game_rules">
        The game ends when any of the following rules apply:
        \n• A player P wins when:
            \n\t– P’s pieces occupy three special cells, or
            \n\t– P’s opponent’s pieces are all either killed or frozen and P has at least one non-killed and non-frozen piece
        \n• If, when it’s P’s turn, P cannot move (all of P’s pieces are either killed or frozen) and P’s
        opponent hasn’t won, then the game ends in a draw
    </string>

    <string name="player">HUMAN PLAYER</string>
    <string name="ai_player">COMPUTER</string>
    <string name="set_your_name">SET HERE YOUR NAME</string>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>

</resources>
